I think it'll be a relief to some people and a disappointment to others
أعتقد أنها ستكون معيناً لبعض الناس وخيبة أمل لآخرين
that I'm not going to talk about vaginas today.
لن أتحدث لكم عن المهابل اليوم
I began "The Vagina Monologues" because I was worried about vaginas.
بدأت بمناجاة المهبل لأنني كنت قلقة عليه
I'm very worried today about this notion, this world,
أنا قلقة جداً اليوم على هذه الفكرة، هذا العالم
this prevailing kind of force of security.
الذي يسوده نوع من القوة الأمنية
I see this word, hear this word, feel this word everywhere.
أرى هذه الكلمة ، أسمع هذه الكلمة ، أشعر بهذه الكلمة في كل مكان
Real security, security checks, security watch, security clearance.
الأمن الحقيقي، عمليات تفتيش أمنية، مراقبة أمنية، تصريح أمني
Why has all this focus on security made me feel so much more insecure?
لماذا كل هذا التركيز على الأمن جعلني أشعر بعدم أمان أكثر؟
What does anyone mean when they talk about real security?
ماذا يعني كل شخص عندما يتحدثوا عن الأمن الحقيقي؟
And why have we, as Americans particularly,
ولماذا الأمريكيين تحديداً،
become a nation that strives for security above all else?
يصبحوا الأمة التي تسعى للأمن فوق كل شئ؟
In fact, I think that security is elusive. It's impossible.
في الحقيقة، أعتقد أن الأمن عبارة عن وهم، أنه مستحيل
We all die. We all get old. We all get sick. People leave us.
كلنا نموت. كلنا نشيخ. كلنا نمرض. يفارقنا الناس
People change us. Nothing is secure.
يغيّرنا الناس. لا شئ آمن
And that's actually the good news.
وهذا في الحقيقة شئ جيد
This is, of course, unless your whole life is about being secure.
هذا هو، بالطبع، إلا اذا كانت كل حياتك هي أن تصبح آمناً
I think that when that is the focus of your life,
أعتقد أنه عندما يكون هذا تركيز حياتك
these are the things that happen.
ستحدث هذه الأشياء.
You can't travel very far or venture too far outside a certain circle.
لا تستطيع السفر أو المغامرة بعيداً عن دائرة محددة.
You can't allow too many conflicting ideas into your mind at one time,
لن تسمح بالكثير من الأفكار المتضاربة تدور في ذهنك في وقت واحد
as they might confuse you or challenge you.
لأنها ربما تربكك وتهددك
You can't open yourself to new experiences, new people,
لا تستطيع تقبل تجارب جديد، أناس جدد
new ways of doing things -- they might take you off course.
طريقة جديدة لفعل الأشياء. ربما تأخذك بالطبع
You can't not know who you are, so you cling to hard-matter identity.
لا تستطيع معرفة من أنت، لذا تتمسك بمسألة الهوية
You become a Christian, Muslim, Jew.
تصبح مسيحي، مسلم، يهودي
You're an Indian, Egyptian, Italian, American.
أنت هندي، مصري، إيطالي، أمريكي.
You're a heterosexual or a homosexual, or you never have sex.
أنت مثلي أو محب للجنس الآخر، أو لم تمارس الجنس إطلاقاً
Or at least, that's what you say when you identify yourself.
أو على الأقل، هذا ما تقوله عندما تقدّم نفسك
You become part of an "us."
تصبح جزء من "نحن"
In order to be secure, you defend against "them."
من أجل أن تصبح آمناً، أنت تقاتل ضد "هم"
You cling to your land because it is your secure place.
تتمسك بأرضك لأنها مكانك الآمن
You must fight anyone who encroaches upon it.
عليك محاربة كل من يعتدي عليها
You become your nation. You become your religion.
أنت تصبح بلادك. أنت تصبح ديانتك
You become whatever it is that will freeze you, numb you
أنت تصبح أي شئ يجمّدك، يخدّرك
and protect you from doubt or change.
ويحميك من الشك أو التغيير.
But all this does, actually, is shut down your mind.
لكن هل كل هذا في الواقع، يغلق عقلك.
In reality, it does not really make you safer.
في الواقع، لا تجعلك في الحقيقة أكثر أمناً.
I was in Sri Lanka, for example, three days after the tsunami,
كنت في سيريلانكا، على سبيل المثال، بعد ثلاثة أيام من التسونامي،
and I was standing on the beaches
كنت أقف على الشواطئ
and it was absolutely clear that, in a matter of five minutes,
وكان واضحاً جداً أنه في غضون خمس دقائق،
a 30-foot wave could rise up
قد ترتفع موجة علوّها 30 قدماً
and desecrate a people, a population and lives.
وتنتهك حياة أحد من الناس، وحياة السكان.
All this striving for security, in fact,
كل هذا السعي من أجل الأمن، في الحقيقة
has made you much more insecure
جعلكم أقل أمناً بكثير
because now you have to watch out all the time.
لأن الآن، يتعين عليك الحرص في كل الأوقات.
There are people not like you -- people who you now call enemies.
هناك بشر ليسو مثلك. بشر تسميهم الآن بالأعداء،
You have places you cannot go, thoughts you cannot think,
هناك أماكن لا تستطيع الذهاب اليها، أفكار لا تستطيع التفكير بها،
worlds that you can no longer inhabit.
عوالم لم يعد بإمكانك العيش فيها.
And so you spend your days fighting things off, defending your territory
ولذا تقضي أيامك في الخروج للقتال، والدفاع عن أراضيك،
and becoming more entrenched in your fundamental thinking.
وتصبح أكثر رسوخاً في تفكيرك الأصولي.
Your days become devoted to protecting yourself.
تصبح أيامك مكرسة لحماية نفسك.
This becomes your mission. That is all you do.
تصبح هذه هي مهمتك. هذا كل ما تفعله.
Ideas get shorter. They become sound bytes.
الأفكار تصبح أقصر. تصبح مثل البايتات.
There are evildoers and saints, criminals and victims.
هناك الظالمين والقديسين، المجرمين والضحايا.
There are those who, if they're not with us, are against us.
هناك الناس، الذين ، إن لم يكونوا معنا، فهم ضدنا.
It gets easier to hurt people because you do not feel what's inside them.
يصبح من السهل إيذاء الناس لأنك لا تحس بدواخلهم.
It gets easier to lock them up, force them to be naked, humiliate them,
من السهل سجنهم، إجبارهم على التعرّي، إهانتهم،
occupy them, invade them and kill them,
إحتلالهم، غزوهم وقتلهم
because they are only obstacles now to your security.
لأنهم العقبة الوحيدة الآن أمام أمنك.
In six years, I've had the extraordinary privilege through V-Day,
في ستة سنوات، حصلت على تصريح فوق عادي عبر ال V-Day
a global movement against [violence against] women,
وهي حركة عالمية ضد العنف على النساء،
to travel probably to 60 countries,
للسفر تقريباً الى 60 دولة،
and spend a great deal of time in different portions.
وقضيت وقتاً عظيماً في الكثير من الأنحاء.
I've met women and men all over this planet,
إلتقيت بنساء ورجال من كل كوكب الأرض،
who through various circumstances --
الذين مروا بالعديد من الظروف،
war, poverty, racism, multiple forms of violence --
الحرب، الفقر، العنصرية، أنواع متعددة من العنف،
have never known security,
لم يعرفوا أبداً الأمن،
or have had their illusion of security forever devastated.
أو كان لهم وهم الأمن المدمّر الى الأبد.
I've spent time with women in Afghanistan under the Taliban,
قضيت وقتاً مع نساء في أفغانستان تحت حكم طالبان،
who were essentially brutalized and censored.
تعرضن لمعاملة وحشية ومراقبة.
I've been in Bosnian refugee camps.
ذهبت الى معسكرات اللاجئين في البوسنة.
I was with women in Pakistan
كنت مع نساء في باكستان
who have had their faces melted off with acid.
اللاتي شوّهت وجوههن بالحامض.
I've been with girls all across America who were date-raped,
كنت مع بنات عبر كل أمريكا اللاتي تعرضن للإغتصاب
or raped by their best friends when they were drugged one night.
أو تم إغتصابهن بواسطة أعزّ الأصدقاء عندما تم تخديرهن لليلة واحدة.
One of the amazing things that I've discovered in my travels
أحد الأشياء المدهشة التي أكتشفتها في رحلاتي
is that there is this emerging species.
هو وجود هذه الأنواع في النشوء.
I loved when he was talking about this other world that's right next to this world.
أحببت حديثه عن هذا العالم الآخر الذي بجانب هذا العالم .
I've discovered these people, who, in V-Day world,
أكتشفت أؤلئك الناس، في عالم V-Day،
we call Vagina Warriors.
نسميهم مقاتلي المهبل.
These particular people, rather than getting AK-47s,
أؤلئك الناس المحددين، بدلاً عن أخذ بنادق- 47
or weapons of mass destruction, or machetes,
أو أسلحة دمار شامل أو مناجل،
in the spirit of the warrior, have gone into the center, the heart of pain, of loss.
بروح المحارب، ذهبوا الى المركز، الى قلب الألم، والخسارة.
They have grieved it, they have died into it,
لقد حزنوا عليها، وماتوا فيها،
and allowed and encouraged poison to turn into medicine.
وسمحوا وشجعوا السم أن يتحول الى دواء.
They have used the fuel of their pain to begin to redirect that energy
لقد أستخدموا وقود آلامهم للبدء في إعادة توجيه الطاقة
towards another mission and another trajectory.
بإتجاه مهمة أخرى وإحداثيات أخرى.
These warriors now devote themselves and their lives
هؤلاء المحاربين الآن يكرسون أنفسهم وحياتهم
to making sure what happened to them doesn't happen to anyone else.
للتأكد بأن ما حدث لهم، لا يحدث لأي شخص آخر.
There are thousands if not millions of them on the planet.
هناك الآلاف إن لم يكن الملايين منهم على الأرض.
I venture there are many in this room.
أراهن بأن العديد منهم في هذه القاعة.
They have a fierceness and a freedom
لديهم من الضراوة والحرية
that I believe is the bedrock of a new paradigm.
التي أعتقد أنها أساس النموذج الجديد.
They have broken out of the existing frame of victim and perpetrator.
لقد كسروا الحواجز الموجودة للضحية والجاني.
Their own personal security is not their end goal,
أمنهم الشخصي ليس هدفهم النهائي،
and because of that, because, rather than worrying about security,
وبسبب ذلك، بدلاً عن القلق بشأن الأمن،
because the transformation of suffering is their end goal,
لأن تبديل المعاناة هو هدفهم النهائي،
I actually believe they are creating real safety
أعتقد أنهم يصنعون أماناً حقيقياً
and a whole new idea of security.
وفكرة جديدة تماماً للأمن.
I want to talk about a few of these people that I've met.
أود الحديث عن بعض هؤلاء الناس الذين التقيتهم.
Tomorrow, I am going to Cairo,
غداً سأذهب الى القاهرة،
and I'm so moved that I will be with women in Cairo
وأنا مُثارة بشدة لأنني سألتقي بنساء في القاهرة
who are V-Day women, who are opening the first safe house
من نساء V-day، اللائي سيفتتحن أول بيت آمن
for battered women in the Middle East.
للنساء اللواتي يتعرضن للعنف في الشرق الأوسط.
That will happen because women in Cairo made a decision to stand up
سيحدث هذا لأن نساء في القاهرة أتخذن قرار الوقوف
and put themselves on the line,
ووضع أنفسهن على الخط
and talk about the degree of violence that is happening in Egypt,
والتحدث عن درجة العنف الذي يحدث في مصر
and were willing to be attacked and criticized.
وكانوا على إستعداد ليُهجم عليهن وينتقدن،
And through their work over the last years,
وعبر عملهن خلال السنوات الماضية،
this is not only happening that this house is opening,
ليس فقط ما يحدث إفتتاح هذا البيت،
but it's being supported by many factions of the society
لكنه مدعوم من قبل العديد من شرائح المجتمع
who never would have supported it.
التي لم تكن قد تدعمها.
Women in Uganda this year,
النساء في يوغندا هذه السنة
who put on "The Vagina Monologues" during V-Day,
اللاتي عقدن مناجاة المهبل خلال V-Day
actually evoked the wrath of the government.
فعلاً أثاروا غضب الحكومة.
And, I love this story so much.
و، أحب هذه الحكاية كثيراً.
There was a cabinet meeting and a meeting of the presidents
كان هناك إجتماع للحكومة ولقاء للرؤساء
to talk about whether "Vaginas" could come to Uganda.
للحديث حول إمكانية مجئ مسرحية المهابل الى يوغندا
And in this meeting -- it went on for weeks in the press,
وفي هذا الإجتماع، الذي استمر أسابيع في الإعلام،
two weeks where there was huge discussion.
أسبوعين حيث دار نقاش ضخم.
The government finally made a decision
الحكومة أخيراً أخذت قرارها
that "The Vagina Monologues" could not be performed in Uganda.
بأن مسرحية مناجاة المهابل لا يمكن أن تقام في يوغندا.
But the amazing news was that because they had stood up, these women,
لكن الأخبار المدهشة كان بسبب وقوف النساء،
and because they had been willing to risk their security,
وبسبب أنهم كانوا على إستعداد للمخاطرة بسلامتهن،
it began a discussion that not only happened in Uganda,
لقد أبتدرت نقاشاً لم يدر فقط في يوغندا،
but all of Africa.
لكن في كل أفريقيا.
As a result, this production, which had already sold out,
ونتيجة لذلك، هذا العرض الذي تم بيع تذاكره بالفعل،
every single person in that 800-seat audience, except for 10 people,
أي شخص في الحضور البالغ عددهم 800، بإستثناء عشرة أشخاص،
made a decision to keep the money.
أخذ قرار بعد إسترداد المال.
They raised 10,000 dollars on a production that never occurred.
لقد جمعوا 10,000$ لعرض لم يتم.
There's a young woman named Carrie Rethlefsen in Minnesota.
هناك شابة تسمى كيري روفلسون في مينيستوتا.
She's a high school student.
وهي طالبة في الثانوية العليا.
She had seen "The Vagina Monologues" and she was really moved. And as a result,
لقد شاهدت مسرحية مناجاة المهابل وأُثيرت بالفعل، ونتيجة لذلك،
she wore an "I heart my vagina" button to her high school in Minnesota.
لبست قميص ، أنا أحب مهبلي في مدرستها الثانوية في مينيستوتا
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
She was basically threatened to be expelled from school.
كانت أساساً مهددة بالطرد من المدرسة.
They told her she couldn't love her vagina in high school,
أخبروها بأنها لم تتمكن من حب مهبلها في المدرسة الثانوية،
that it was not a legal thing, that it was not a moral thing,
لم يكن هذا شيئاً قانونياً، لم يكن شيئاً أخلاقياً،
that it was not a good thing.
لم يكن هذا شيئاً جيداً.
So she really struggled with this, what to do,
لذا فقد عانت حقيقةً مع هذا، ماذا تفعل،
because she was a senior and she was doing well in her school
لأنها كانت في صف متقدم ومتفوقة في مدرستها
and she was threatened expulsion. So what she did is she got all her friends together --
وكانت مهددة بالطرد، لذا ما فعلته، هو أنها جمعت كل أصدقائها سوياً،
I believe it was 100, 150 students
أعتقد أنهم كانوا 100، 150 طالباً،
all wore "I love my vagina" T-shirts,
ولبسوا قميص أحب مهبلي،
and the boys wore "I love her vagina" T-shirts to school.
ولبس الشباب قميص أحب مهبلها الى المدرسة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now this seems like a fairly, you know, frivolous,
الآن يبدو هذا الى حد ما، تعلمون، تافه،
but what happened as a result of that, is that that school now
لكن ماذا حدث كنتيجة لذلك، أن تلك المدرسة الآن
is forming a sex education class. It's beginning to talk about sex,
تشكّل فصلاً دراسياً عن الجنس، بدأت الحديث عن الجنس،
it's beginning to look at why it would be wrong
أنها بداية النظر حول لماذا سيكون خطاءً
for a young high school girl to talk about her vagina publicly
لطالبة شابة في الثانوية الحديث عن مهبلها على الملأ
or to say that she loved her vagina publicly.
أو أن تقول أنها تحب مهبلها في العلن.
I know I've talked about Agnes here before,
أعرف أنني تحدثت عن آغنس من قبل،
but I want to give you an update on Agnes.
لكني أريد تقديم بعض التحديثات لكم عن آغنس.
I met Agnes three years ago in the Rift Valley.
قابلت آغنس قبل ثلاث سنوات في ريفت فالي.
When she was a young girl, she had been mutilated against her will.
عندما كانت شابة فتية، قاموا بتشويهها على خلاف رغبتها.
That mutilation of her clitoris
ذلك التشويه لبظرها
had actually obviously impacted her life
كان من الواضح أنه أثّر على حياتها
and changed it in a way that was devastating.
وغيرها بطريقة كانت مدمّرة.
She made a decision not to go and get a razor or a glass shard,
وقررت أن لا تذهب لأخذ شفرة أو زجاج مهشّم،
but to devote her life to stopping that happening to other girls.
لكن لتكريس حياتها لعدم حدوث ذلك لغيرها من الفتيات.
For eight years, she walked through the Rift Valley.
لثماني سنوات، طافت عبر ريفت فالي.
She had this amazing box that she carried and it had a
كان لديها ذلك الصندوق المدهش الذي تحمله ولديها
torso of a woman's body in it, a half a torso,
تمثال لجسم المرأة بداخله، نصف تمثال،
and she would teach people, everywhere she went,
وتعلّم الناس في كل مكان ذهبت أليه ،
what a healthy vagina looked like and what a mutilated vagina looked like.
كيف يبدو شكل المهبل المعافى وكيف يبدو المهبل المشوّه.
In the years that she walked, she educated parents, mothers, fathers.
خلال السنوات التي طافت فيها، علّمت الوالدين، الأمهات، الآباء ،
She saved 1,500 girls from being cut.
لقد أنقذت 1,500 فتاة من الختان.
When V-Day met her, we asked her how we could support her
عندما إلتقتها V-Day، سألناها عن كيفية دعمها
and she said, "Well, if you got me a Jeep,
وأجابت، "حسناً، اذا أحضرتم لي سيارة جيب،
I could get around a lot faster." So, we bought her a Jeep.
يمكنني الطواف بصورة أسرع." لذا أشترينا لها سيارة جيب.
In the year she had the Jeep, she saved 4,500 girls from being cut.
في السنة التي أشترينا لها السيارة الجيب، أنقذت 4,500 فتاة من الختان.
So, we said, what else could we do?
لذا قلنا، ماذا أيضاً يمكننا أن نفعل؟
She said, "If you help me get money, I could open a house."
قالت، " اذا ساعدتوني للحصول على المال، يمكنني فتح بيت."
Three years ago, Agnes opened a safe house in Africa to stop mutilation.
بعد ثلاث سنوات، آغنس أفتتحت بيت آمناً في أفريقيا لإيقاف التشويه.
When she began her mission eight years ago, she was reviled,
عندما بدأت مهمتها قبل ثماني سنوات، كانت تُلعن،
she was detested, she was completely slandered in her community.
كانت مدمّرة، كانت مكروهة جداً في مجتمعها.
I am proud to tell you that six months ago,
أنا فخورة بأن أخبركم أنه قبل ستة أشهر،
she was elected the deputy mayor of Narok.
تم إنتخابها كنائب عمدة ناروك.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I think what I'm trying to say here
أعتقد أن ما أحاول قوله هنا،
is that if your end goal is security,
أنه اذا كان هدفك النهائي هو الأمن،
and if that's all you're focusing on, what ends up happening
وهذا كل شئ تركز فيه، ما سينتهي بك الحال فيه،
is that you create not only more insecurity in other people,
هو أنك ليس فقط تصنع عدم أمان للآخرين،
but you make yourself far more insecure.
لكن تجعل نفسك أقل أمناً بشدة.
Real security is contemplating death, not pretending it doesn't exist.
الأمن الحقيقي هو التفكير في الموت، ليس التظاهر بعد وجوده.
Not running from loss, but entering grief, surrendering to sorrow.
ليس الهروب من الخسارة، لكن الدخول في الكآبة، الإستسلام الى الأسى.
Real security is not knowing something, when you don't know it.
الأمن الحقيقي ليس معرفة شئ عندما لا تعرفه.
Real security is hungering for connection rather than power.
الأمن الحقيقي هو التعطش للإتصال بدلاً عن السلطة.
It cannot be bought or arranged or made with bombs.
لا يمكن شراؤه، أو ترتيبه أو صنعه بالقنابل.
It is deeper, it is a process, it is acute awareness
أنه أعمق، أنه عملية مستمرة ، أنه الوعي الحاد
that we are all utterly inter-bended,
الذي نحن جميعنا بين مُنحناه
and one action by one being in one tiny town
وكل عمل يقوم به شخص واحد في مدينة صغيرة،
has consequences everywhere.
له تبعات في أماكن أخرى.
Real security is not only being able
الأمن الحقيقي ليس فقط أن تكون قادراً
to tolerate mystery, complexity, ambiguity, but hungering for them
على تحمّل الغموض، التعقيد، الشكوك، والتعطش لهم.
and only trusting a situation when they are present.
وفقط الثقة في الأحوال عندما تكون حاضرة.
Something happened when I began traveling in V-Day, eight years ago. I got lost.
شئ حدث عندما بدأت الترحال في V-Day قبل ثماني سنوات. لقد ضعت.
I remember being on a plane going from Kenya to South Africa,
أتذكر أنني كنت في طائرة ذاهبة من كينيا الى جنوب أفريقيا،
and I had no idea where I was.
ولم يكن لدي فكرة عن أين كنت.
I didn't know where I was going, where I'd come from,
لم أعرف الى أين كنت ذاهبة، من أين أتيت،
and I panicked. I had a total anxiety attack.
وذُعرت، أصبت كلياً بالقلق.
And then I suddenly realized that it absolutely didn't matter
وبعدها فجأة أدركت أنه لا فرق على الإطلاق
where I was going, or where I had come from
أين كنت ذاهبة، أو من أين أتيت
because we are all essentially permanently displaced people.
لأننا في الاساس كنّا جميعاً نازحين دائمين.
All of us are refugees.
كلنا لاجئين.
We come from somewhere and we are hopefully traveling all the time,
لقد أتينا من مكان ما ونسافر على أمل كل الأوقات،
moving towards a new place.
نذهب بإتجاه أماكن جديدة.
Freedom means I may not be identified as any one group,
الحُرية تعني أنني ربما لا يتم تعريفي كأي مجموعة واحدة،
but that I can visit and find myself in every group.
لا أن بإمكاني زيارة وإيجاد نفسي في كل مجموعة.
It does not mean that I don't have values or beliefs,
لا تعني أنه ليس لدي قيّم أو معتقدات،
but it does mean I am not hardened around them.
لكنها تعني أنني لست متصلبة حولهم.
I do not use them as weapons.
أن لا أستخدمهم كسلاح.
In the shared future, it will be just that, shared.
في المستقبل المشترك، سيكون فقط هكذا، مشترك.
The end goal will [be] becoming vulnerable,
الهدف النهائي سوف يصبح عرضة ،
realizing the place of our connection to one another,
تحقيق المكان لإتصالاتنا ببعضنا،
rather than becoming secure, in control and alone.
بدلاً عن أن نصبح آمنين، متحكمين، ووحيدين.
Thank you very much.
شكراً جزيلاً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Chris Anderson: And how are you doing? Are you exhausted?
وكيف حالك؟ هل أنت مرهقة؟
On a typical day, do you wake up with hope or gloom?
في اليوم العادي، هل تستيقظي على الأمل أم الكآبة؟
Eve Ensler: You know, I think Carl Jung once said
تعرف، أعتقد أن كارل جونغ قالت ذات مرة
that in order to survive the twentieth century,
أنه من أجل العيش في القرن العشرين،
we have to live with two existing thoughts, opposite thoughts, at the same time.
يتوجب علينا التعايش مع فكرتين، متضادتين، في نفس الوقت.
And I think part of what I'm learning in this process
وأعتقد أن جزء مما أتعلمه في هذه العملية،
is that one must allow oneself to feel grief.
أن على الشخص أن يسمح لنفسه أن يشعر بالحزن.
And I think as long as I keep grieving, and weeping,
وأعتقد مادمت أحتفظ بالحزن، والبكاء،
and then moving on, I'm fine.
وبعدها المُضي قدماً، أنا بخير.
When I start to pretend that what I'm seeing isn't impacting me,
عندما بدأت أتظاهر بأن ما أراه لا يؤثر عليّ،
and isn't changing my heart, then I get in trouble.
ولا يغيّر قلبي، حينها أدخل في مشكلة
Because when you spend a lot of time going from place to place,
لأنه عندما تقضي الكثير من الزمن تتنقل من مكان الى مكان،
country to country, and city to city,
دولة الى دولة، ومدينة الى مدينة،
the degree to which women, for example, are violated,
الدرجة التي عليها المرأة، كمثال، منتهكة الحقوق،
and the epidemic of it, and the kind of ordinariness of it,
والوباء عليها، وعمومية ذلك،
is so devastating to one's soul that you have to take the time,
أنه مدمّر جداً لروح الإنسان، بحيث تأخذ وقتاً،
or I have to take the time now, to process that.
أو عليّ أخذ الوقت الآن، لمعالجة ذلك.
CA: There are a lot of causes out there in the world that have been talked about,
هناك الكثير من القضايا في العالم التي تحدثوا عنها،
you know, poverty, sickness and so on. You spent eight years on this one.
تعرف، الفقر، المرض وما الى ذلك، أنت قضيتي ثماني سنوات في هذا.
Why this one?
لماذا أخترتي هذا؟
EE: I think that if you think about women,
أعتقد، أذا فكرت في النساء،
women are the primary resource of the planet. They give birth,
النساء هن المصدر الأساس للأرض، أنهن يلدن،
we come from them, they are mothers, they are visionaries,
نحن نأتي منهن، هن الأمهات، والرؤية،
they are the future. If you think that the U.N. now says
هن المستقبل. اذا فكرت بأن تقول الأمم المتحدة
that one out of three women on the planet
بأن أحدى ثلاث نساء على الأرض
will be raped or beaten in their lifetime,
سيتم إغتصابها أو ضربها خلال حياتها،
we're talking about the desecration of the primary resource of the planet,
فأنت تتحدث عن تدنيس المصدر الأساسي للأرض،
we're talking about the place where we come from, we're talking about parenting.
نحن نتحدث عن الأماكن التي نأتي منها، نتحدث عن تربية الأطفال.
Imagine that you've been raped and you're bringing up a boy child.
تخيّل بأنك أُغتصبت وستأتي بطفل.
How does it impact your ability to work, or envision a future,
كيف ستتأثر قدرتك على العمل، أو إستشراف المستقبل،
or thrive, as opposed to just survive? What I believe is
أو الإزدهار بدلاً عن البقاء على قيد الحياة؟ ما أعتقده هو
if we could figure out how to make women safe and honor women,
اذا عرفنا كيفية جعل النساء آمنات وأكرمنا النساء ،
it would be parallel or equal to honoring life itself.
سيكون موازياً أو مساوياً لتكريم الحياة نفسها.